Are we a nation of gun nuts or are we just nuts?
Bowling for Columbine is a documentary, drama film directed by Michael Moore.
This is not a film about gun control.
It is a film about the fearful heart and soul of the United States, and the 280 million
Americans lucky enough to have the right to a constitutionally protected Uzi.
From a look at the Columbine High School security camera tapes to the home of Oscar-winning NRA President Charlton Heston, from a young
man who makes homemade napalm with The Anarchist's Cookbook to the murder of a six-year-old girl by another six-year-old.
Bowling for Columbine is a journey through the US, through our past, hoping to
discover why our pursuit of happiness is so riddled with violence.
Self, played by Michael Moore.
Self, played by George H. W. Bush.
Self, played by George W. Bush.
Self - NRA President, played by Charlton Heston.
Self - President of Guatemala, played by Jacobo Árbenz.
Self - Mayor of Sarnia, Ontario, Canada, played by Mike Bradley.
Bowling for Columbine is a 2002 documentary film written,
produced, directed, and narrated by Michael Moore.
The documentary film explores what Moore suggests are the primary causes for the
Columbine High School massacre in 1999 and other acts of gun violence.
He focuses on the background and environment in which the massacre took place and
some common public opinions and assumptions about related issues.
The film also looks into the nature of violence in the
United States, and American violence abroad.
A critical and commercial success, the film brought Moore international attention as a rising filmmaker and won numerous awards, including the Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature,
the Independent Spirit Award for Best Documentary Feature, a special 55th Anniversary Prize at the 2002 Cannes Film Festival, and the César Award for Best Foreign Film.
The film is widely considered one of the greatest documentary films of all time.
The film explores themes of canada, gun, homicide,
mass murder, oklahoma city bombing.
The tone is emotional.